to deeply understand the code basee no
matter what you're using so you could be
you could be trying to call a function
and so you you want to get a completion
at your cursor that just fills in the
fields for that function correctly
pulling them in from all kinds of places
in your code or you could be again
diving into a new repository right and
so you want to understand what is this
repository about give me the high LEL
structure how do the components talk to
each other what's going on here I don't
want to bother reading documentation
which often is missing or out of date I
just want to know what the current state
of the code is or maybe I'm looking uh
for a component that I know I wrote six
months ago but I I can't figure out
where it is I just want to ask chat tell
me where this thing is and it should go
and and find it for me you're listening
to the AI native Dev brought to you by
Tesla
[Music]
hello everyone welcome back to the AI
native Dev today we have a really fun
episode we're going to dig into what
does it mean to build you know a coding
assistant a coding analysis and we'll
have a better explanation of what it is
here to make developers more more
productive as they build with AI and to
do that we have guy gurari who is the
co-founder of augment guy thanks for
joining us here on the podcast yeah very
glad to be here thanks for inviting me
on and we have a slightly unique episode
here in which we have two half hosts
here where we have Dion hey Dion hey
good to be here it's really fun to be
with my favorite Founders who happen to
both be Israeli guys it's world yeah so
guy and I are both guy yeah actually
there's a bit of a story behind that
right we were both in the same group
many years ago not to say so we don't
sound too old but many years ago and
there were four guys named guy and so
none of us were named guy at least for
me I I stayed with Geo on it as the
hashtag but the guy us you managed to
retain just the first name piece yes I
was guer back then but that somehow did
not stick maybe because I didn't try to
propagate it much yes yeah you likeed
the vowel guo at least had that extra o
but you were a guy clearly all a bunch
of nerds it was all about the username
that we happen to have on the on the
Unix system that we Solaris sort of
system cool so we're going to dig into
indeed uh what is to end code if you
will code development on it maybe to get
us started can you tell us guy just a
littleit about augment and what you do
and then we'll go from there yeah
augment is an AI coding assistant that
gives you the whole code based at your
fingertips essentially every way you
interact with augment we try to make it
seem like uh the models really
understand your full code base and so
what that means is that then you can go
and make changes to the code write new
code and do that all with confidence
without having to retain the whole code
base in your head so just to give I
think we'll go more deeply into it but
just just to give one example where we
see this help a lot if I need to go into
a new part of the code base for example
that I've never touched before with
augment I can get up to speed and start
making changes with confidence usually
within a few hours to a day versus
something that would take me sometimes a
week or longer just to get up to speed
on what's happening in that part of the
code base or in a new repository I'm
looking at and so that's maybe a way to
summarize it's for us it's about the
context making the context from the
codebase available to the model leads to
much better results as far as we can
tell cool super interesting and yeah
we're going to dig a lot more into that
and I guess maybe veering a little bit
backwards from augment you've had one of
the earlier exposures to llm still in
your role in Google can you tell us a
little bit about the I guess how you
found out about llms you started
building them and I guess maybe when is
it that you learned to appreciate their
power yeah so I joined Google this was 6
years ago very excited about machine
learning I thought this was a a
scientific revolution that was happening
of a once in a-lifetime thing and I was
very excited to be part of it back then
the discussion was really centered a lot
more from my perspective on Vision
models convolutional neural networks
through all the rage and so I was doing
a lot of research work on that and then
when gpt3 came out for me that was a
pivotal moment because it became clear
that there's something very special
about language models based on
Transformers
where suddenly instead of having to
fine-tune the model to do something that
you like you can prompt it you can do F
shot prompting which really cut down on
the amount of time you had to spend with
the model uh to get something out of it
uh and so me and the the team at Google
we we really pivoted our work toward
language models and we started
evaluating them we started being more
involved in training the large language
models I was involved in some of the
training of the large models at Google
uh and kind of through that work I
became convinced that yes this is it
this is really the new heart I would say
of the AI Revolution is these generative
models that are very general and can
generate a lot of text for you and I
guess how quickly did it become a parent
that not only are they powerful these
llms but they can actually help with
code they can help with software
development yeah so I think that
certainly took some time I think that to
me and to to folks I at least interacted
with that was not obvious from the
beginning and I think maybe the reason
why is that there was something about
reasoning heavy tasks that seemed more
remote or more Out Of Reach or harder
there are uh many people who've done
very good work on reasoning tasks uh for
many years trying to do a lot of
sometimes you might call it feature
engineering sometimes you might call it
find architectures to solve heart
reasoning tasks a lot of symbolic work
semantic analysis on code and on math
and so on and still that work is I would
say a lot of it is still relevant but I
think it was the big surprise certainly
to me and I think also to many others is
the the degree to which you can apply
scale of compute and scale of data and
solve hard reasoning tasks and so code
is an example of that other examples of
that are math and science I think
probably most people were surprised by
how good you can make these models using
very general techniques the same
techniques that you use to get them to
write poetry to get them to edit law
documents and so on and help them solve
reasoning tasks I think code was a part
of that I think one of the earliest
indications that there was something
interesting happening was the Codex
model and then at Google we had our own
code models where we saw some success
but the rate of progress on code has
been surprising would say but also these
other models they were not buil on
language right like they were bu on more
I don't know what the terms is it the
neuros symbolic or is like I don't know
like I'm I'm probably abusing the terms
but they were understanding the code
breaking it down into some sort of
symbolic representation of the code and
then analyzing on those and and the llms
as I my kind of layman data science
understanding here like they were very
different they jumped into completing
treating code AS text is is that a
correct kind of representation here
that's exactly right this is part of so
people I think widely in the community
thought that yes you need to do
something special to deal with code and
also to deal with math and other hard
reasoning tasks neuros symbolic
approaches were that was one big
approach there were also purely symbolic
approaches and yes the surprise is that
when you take a large language models
and you just use the same general
techniques the same architecture the
same methods of training that you use on
other text domains you get excellent
results if you scale it up yes so that
was I I agree with that description yeah
and you worked on the research that went
into the another paper around reasoning
is that correct yes so we worked on
another hard reasoning domain solving
math and science questions and for us
that was the Eureka moment in that
domain which was yes we the work
involved again scaling up the data
downloading all of the archive papers
all the research papers we could find
scanning the internet for all the papers
that had something to do with
mathematics which at Google all the
infrastructure makes that
straightforward to do and then train the
largest model we could put our hands on
back then it was the Paul model from
Google train it on all that data and see
what it can do in terms of math and we
were blown away by the quality you can
extract from these very general models
train in a very general way we got these
models to pass University entrance exams
based on these techniques and so for me
that was the point where I thought oh if
we can do this on reasoning you can do
this probably on code and on many other
domains it's it's not that reasoning
it's this uh special thing the general
techniques are really powerful enough to
address those problems as well very cool
and I realized you know that I skipped
the part in which I explained your
connection to augment on it so listeners
may be aware that Dion is recently
joined and you're a Phil CTO and you're
doing uh a whole bunch of good things
over here and before that you were at
augment and you were leading a lot of
the product over there so you end up
being here knowing all sorts of
perspectives about this domain exactly
and when guy was talk about at the high
level the importance of context and the
like I just want to highlight that the
proof is in the pudding with all of
these things when I first met with the
augment team and seeing the product even
back then and it's just gotten obviously
uh increasingly better over time the
feel of using that product compared to
other coding assistants that are out
there is just a very different
experience and I noticed that as of
today Friday January 17th you can selfs
serve and actually try it out yourself
and I just really recommend downloading
it running on a real repo and doing a
real task and that's where you get to
feel the difference right it's the
analogy I always give is there were lots
of search engines and then Google came
along and it felt a little bit different
and that was my even early experience
with augment and that's where I get to
meet up with guy and Igor the other
co-founder and then the amazing research
team that they' built to pull this off
that you know that we'll get into more
detail yeah it's a pleasure to to be
here with both guys so I guess I think
we've been attempting this topic for
long enough on it let's dig into the
context give context on context so what
is this special sauce like when you talk
about context matters you talk about
that being you know something that
provides sort of different level of
magic when you use it tell us a bit more
about what that means and and maybe how
it defers than maybe the normal way in
which Els might operate yeah system
might operate yeah so I'd say the there
are few things that go into it uh one is
just the basic ability to deeply
understand the code base no matter what
you're using so you could be trying to
call a function and so you want to get a
completion at your cursor that just
fills in the fields for that function
correctly pulling them in from all kinds
of places in your code or you could be
again diving into a new repository right
and so you want to understand what is
this repository about give me the high
level structure how do the components
talk to each other what's going on here
I don't want to bother reading
documentation which often is missing or
out of date I just want to know what the
current state of the code is or maybe
I'm looking uh for a component that I
know I wrote six months ago but I I
can't figure out where it is I just want
to ask chat tell me where this thing is
and it should go and and find it for me
so all these things require context all
these things require analyzing the full
code base and being able to do that in a
way to correctly answer questions and
write generate code BAS based on it you
have to have the code whole code base in
there and we know that the models
context Windows today and probably in
the foreseeable future are not large
enough to fit real large scale complex
code bases in there and so we have to
use other techniques in order to make
the models aware of all that context so
one side of it is yes how can we pull in
the correct context from the repository
to answer the particular query to
address the particular completion I'd
say the other side of it that we found
also very important is in the
interactivity so that means first of all
it has to be really fast if it's not
fast it it quickly gets annoying even if
the quality is good and so there's a lot
of engineering and research effort that
goes into that and there's also a real
time aspect to it if I'm typing away a
function in one file and I switch to my
unitest file and I want to write the
test for that I don't want to have to
tell the model I just wrote this
function please write the test for me it
should know that function is something I
just wrote it should follow me along as
I'm editing and so the codebase
awareness should also be aware of what
I'm doing it should be aware of the real
time nature of the work getting that all
to work together and folks who have
worked on rag they know that you need to
an indexing step and that indexing step
can be challenging and can take a while
getting all that to to work together and
getting it to work within hundreds of
milliseconds and getting that whole
thing to come together as a kind of
delightful user experience this is where
the challenge is it's like get the
quality right get the speed right get
the real time aspect of it and all these
things have to come together on any
possible task a developer might want to
do in their code base yeah yeah so I
guess this is super interesting and a
few clarifying questions one is does the
context also make you a better developer
or just a better developer in this
environment is it
I can understand or easy to understand
how if I'm a super skill developer and I
go into a brand new organization I've
never written code in their codebase
then I would be at a certain level maybe
after five years working in this code
base on it I will know how to write
better code in this company I wouldn't
be a better developer maybe minus what
I've learned in these five years but I
would be better tuned in better tune my
with my surrounding but is the the same
is that the way to think about this
context analysis it's more about
understanding like being a better
developer in this organization or are
there elements of it that that you feel
have the promise of actually just being
a better developer almost like the
context of the world my natural thinking
is like the context of the world gets
encoded into the llms that's what they
bring with it and you're talking about
understanding the
org is that right yes that's right so I
would say at this point we're starting
with code based awareness which is what
I've I've been describing there are a
lot of other sources of information for
that organization that can be relevant
we can talk about them too but yes it is
about aligning the model in some sense
to the organization's knowledge
everything else that's about the world
usually is already baked into the model
I would say the way I've seen this make
me a better developer is by making my
learning process faster and so often the
model will notice or pick up on certain
useful patterns or tricks or just good
things that people have done around the
code base and will surface them through
these suggestions this process I think
happens naturally right you talk to your
co-workers you read other people's code
you learn I would say that the context
awareness accelerates that process uh
and of course in any organization there
are things that are specific to that
organization but then there are also
many useful patterns right whenever we
work at a company we learn things that
we then take with us to our next role I
would say this accelerates that process
but it it's it's less about yes this
will the context awareness will help me
learn what the latest methods are in my
field it's it's less about that and I
definitely saw that with customers right
where I remember one developer us an
arugment was like I heard that
JavaScript had added sets and I kept
thinking like I want to use this
sometime and I never did I never got
around to it because it wasn't outside
of when I was actually doing things but
then all of a sudden as I'm writing code
that set apply it's suggesting that and
yes that's baked into the overall piece
but also a lot of your co-workers are
pretty smart and do interesting things
and so it does pick up on those things
as well and bring that across I
definitely agree with guy on just like
the the whole kind of accelerating your
learning and I definitely felt that even
things that I thought I had some
expertise in like typescript and the
like it was just teaching me things that
felt like if I was pair programming with
colleagues and in this case it's like a
mesh of the intelligence of all of my
colleagues all at once to to help about
yeah it's interesting I guess the
picture that comes to mind is more about
Focus if you know everything in the
world and you might have there's all the
craft of software development but then
there's a a focusing element of looking
at the aspects of The Craft of software
development that matter more in in this
specific organization in the specific
setting and so maybe you now understand
or or the system is now able to
understand that that is the type of
specialization that you might want to
bring to four it does though very much
beg yeah never organization you take a
bunch of things that you want to take
with you to the next organization and
there's a whole pile of things that you
learn to not do in the next organization
how how do you existing codebase
existing Enterprise scale 20 year old
code bases on it have a lot of stuff in
it that you absolutely do not want new
codes to replicate how do you clean this
cont how do you deal with that yeah and
so that is the kind of thing where to me
it falls under the bucket of lightweight
steering it's a bit like self-driving
where there there actually a lot of
analogies here to self-driving where
solving the full thing autonomously will
take a while I believe we'll get there
eventually but it will take a while it
will take years probably is my sense and
so something like how can we figure out
automatically which parts of the code
base are more relevant to the kind of
thing we're doing now and which parts
are relevant but we actually want to
avoid them understanding that
automatically will will take time I
think a thing that can help with that is
to go beyond the code base because often
that knowledge is not stored in the code
based right it's stored in slack
conversations it's stored in Google Docs
and all kinds of design documents and so
on so certainly the more context we can
show the model the better it will get at
that but also with these kinds of
questions some lightweight steering
helps and so with augment you can give
the model General guidelines that are
always in effect where you can tell it
when you're doing work for example in
this directory or in this module or in
this component pay less attention to uh
this area of the code because that's old
and of course that's not foolproof just
like everything with AI it will keep
making mistakes but it at least steers
the model more toward that direction so
I think currently it's some combination
of showing them all as much context as
we can plus human steering to translate
into just better better generated code
that follows the organization's patterns
had a bit of a crazy thought jumped to
mind that I wonder if you can take like
I think in the world of whatever in the
tech World some engineering
organizations are perceived as better at
their craft than others there might be
whatever like Netflix used to be very
much at the top of that okay and I
wonder if you can have Netflix sell the
context of their code so say hey this is
what go good code looks like and then I
think there will be quite a few buyers
to say have your autoc completion work
to that tier
even that a little bit too wild and
nobody would ever do that in sharing
that data but yeah even within the
organization right you have that
particular teams where it's or even
people where I just want to be like hey
any PR from Wendy like like prioritize
that more and there was this one of our
the favorite customers who publicly
spoken about this guy Merrick from
webflow who's like a principal engineer
and like deeply understands front end
and runs the front end craft there right
he able to steer things within the
company right and for him it was a huge
aha moment like we talk a lot about like
Junior devs and what it means for them
and learning codebases and then as as
someone like him as a principal engineer
he's able to steer in it's wow this is
I'm virtually paired programming with
all of the new developers of the company
right like he can be going in there okay
when you're using react now this is how
we want you to do things we're using
hooks we're doing it in this certain way
and so given the other the humans the
ability steer what the system is doing I
think is huge and this is if I reflect
this back a little bit what what is
fairly common although quite
painstakingly takes a lot of effort and
so people don't do that as much has been
to try and build all sorts of uh linting
or other roles that might inspect post
writing the code that hey that code that
is written matches our standards matches
our new Norms uh you can do all sorts of
things like that those are old practices
again
not done as often because they're just
hard it's just effort also it's very
annoying to write code and then
afterwards get these 50 aesthetic
differences that changes that you need
to do and so maybe a way to think it
sounds like a way to think about this is
can you reverse that can you take what
you would have written in linting and in
others think about where they come later
in assessments to actually inject them
into the writing process at least to the
extent that the writing process was done
by the coding assistant by augment in
this case to build those out so it's
interesting it's very how again maybe a
silly question from a data center
perspective but you talk about rag I
think people understand fine you Chunk
Up the code in a super super smart
Fashion on it and you make the right
code available at the right time so the
system can make decisions the counter to
that is to train on actual customer code
so that everything is just in the model
why choose Rag and maybe I'll even cremp
I know like part of it is customers
don't like you training on their code
but technologically let's say people did
allow you to train on
their code is there is there a technical
reason to prefer do some real-time
fetching on it over actually taking that
code and lumping it in so the model
knows both the world and yourself yeah
there are a few reasons and early on we
actually did some experiments comparing
the two approaches we found that rag
across the board gave us better results
and there were a few reasons for that so
I think one mental model I've seen that
people have about fine-tuning and this
could be fine-tuning on code or
fine-tuning on your um documents or fine
tuning on anything is that I think
sometimes people imagine that
fine-tuning is a bit like a human
reading the text and learning from it
because when we read a book there's a
lot we get out of that book even if we
just read it once the models when you
fine-tune them on a a corpus of data
let's say code they will scan through it
they might scan through it multiple
times they don't learn things
as deeply as humans do when they just
read it once they will pick up on common
patterns very easily for example if
there's a certain way you like to write
your dock strings and uh most of your
functions have dock strings like that
and then you fine tune on it the model
will be very good at generating the
exact format of dog string that you have
because that's a very common pattern but
fine-tuning the model on your API does
not mean that the mall can now correctly
call your API because that's not what
fine tuning does fine tuning just gets
them all to try to predict the next
token at a time it doesn't teach it
these solving these higher level
reasoning tasks of oh I was trained on
this function and therefore I know how
to call this function just as a simple
example with rag we can actually get to
that we can actually train them all to
understand that when we show it a
function it needs to do a good job when
we try to call that function so
quality-wise we get better results but
then there are also operation
differences this goes back to the real
time nature that I I discussed and to
expand on that a little bit again in a
real large organization every developer
will work on their own branch and every
developer's version of the codebase will
be slightly different and will be
slightly different with my new
differences that they just worked on a
minute ago and to give them the best
possible experience we need the models
to adapt to every developer's Branch at
the state is at currently that if you
want to get that to work well with
fine-tuning that would be difficult that
would require more than normal fine
tuning on the fight training of some
sort which doesn't quite work yeah yeah
maybe you have to do something like
Laura something like parameter efficient
fine tuning where you give every
developer their own small adaptation of
the model but then you're sacrificing
quality based on that because you don't
have as many weights to adapt to the
task so I would say the more you think
about if we saw large quality Gam from
fine-tuning I'd say this the story would
be different but because we didn't see
those and operationally it's a lot
harder to achieve this per user
customization we felt that rag is just a
much better fit for what we were trying
to do yeah yeah interesting yeah we had
Simon last on the podcast the co-founder
of notion talking about notion Ai and
give a different lens on how fine tuning
is tricky it was generally disillusioned
if you will by fine tuning it's really
interesting what you talk about almost
like they become a bit of a drop in the
ocean right and that's the way that I'm
interpreting what you're saying is you
have a lot of information you just added
more information it has a certain amount
of priority over what you've learned
before but it's not a lot of priority
versus rag in which it gets a lot of
priority it was pointing out a different
problem with fine tuning which is it's
very hard to debug have this magic box
you ask it to do something and hopefully
if you gave it a whole bunch of good
examples on it you keep your fingers
crossed and you hope that the magic box
spits out the right answer when you ask
it and maybe it does it statistically
more but when it doesn't you're a bit of
a loss like why didn't you get that
correctly which I found very insightful
in that conversation he was comparing it
to agentic processes and agentic
processes it's easy for me to see how
fine-tuning is much harder to debug than
agentic process because agentic process
it's still a process as a developer it's
easy to relate to say hey this step in
this workflow phase there failed there's
some sequence of steps there's some
terminal output that I can look at and
say hey here it failed when you're using
the product and you're using rag can you
debug is this something that is within
the realm of someone using augment maybe
even not the developer but the owner
whatever it is the admin in the
organization that owns it are they able
to debug when the wrong data gets pulled
in at the wrong time or is that more hey
the the product should take care of this
this should be outside of like the
customers needs yeah we feel like this
is on us to solve and so we love all
feedback that we get from customers
especially when people say hey in this
request I had this completion I had this
chat it got it wrong uh and so then we
will dig in and we will the first
question typically will be was this a
retrieval failure or was this a
generation failure and so it's a bit
like the agents where you can go and
figure out which Step failed you can go
and check did did the retrieval pull in
the right thing and if it didn't then
the failure is there and if it did then
the failure is at the next step where
the model couldn't figure out what to do
with that information that's the most
basic triage um of a bag system yeah um
and so we have all the tooling to do
that yeah we don't generally ask the the
users to do that I have not heard that
idea before that's an interesting one we
haven't gotten requests for that but
generally we try to make users lives as
easy as possible uh still need to
provide the magic on the exactly yeah so
I guess the the market question though
when you look forward it seems very
clear to me and also the product chose
it that indexing your your code base and
extracting it with Rag and a lot of
other smarts uh produces good results uh
however you're not the only one in the
market that claims to be indexing the
database and bringing in those rag
results and we hear it from a lot of
other players and and I guess I I wonder
like how do you see the future of this
do you think the approaches in it
thinking about your own specifically are
sufficiently different in how you would
approach rag how would would do it that
that really there would be one path that
would be very hard to mimic and this
might win it then would be a breakout
level like Dion you mentioned Google as
the example it was massively hard to
mimic what Google has done and yeah
everybody did search some did it
correctly or is this a momentary next
two three five years you have those
opportunities but over time we should
expect rag is fundamentally a good
enough search uh of your code base and
retrieval of it and that really you see
that as an entry point and you would
build Powers elsewhere to be able to
build out from them what do you think we
should expect as an industry yeah to me
it's definitely more of an entry point I
think it's an area where we have an edge
right now as far as we can see from what
we're testing and from what customers
are telling us the feedback we're
getting on even just this week I know we
are in an eval in a customer where we're
being compared and the the the thing I'm
hearing is yes augment is in a different
league in terms of the productivity we
get out of it thanks to the context
ofwar so these are things we we are
hearing regularly uh but my guess is
that yes this is probably temporary
because just the the speed of progress
the rate of progress in this field how
fast things are moving how fast models
are getting faster honestly I'll be
pretty surprised if in a year or two rag
is the thing that differentiates I think
it'll be other things to give one
example of something that we are
preparing to roll out soon this is the
sort of the other side of rag so the
side of rag we talked about is as the
input to the models to give you better
predictions right but the other side of
it which is as important is the ability
of the models to actually go and and
take actions across the code base right
so we're not talking about or your
cursor is right here give me a few lines
of code anymore and also this is users's
expectations at this point please make
the changes for me across the code base
and so that's now a different prediction
task where you need to understand based
on the task in front of me not just what
do I pull in to do a good job
but where do I go in this large complex
codas to make these changes so that's an
example I would say of a component and a
feature will be rolling out soon which
again requires a whole lot of research
to get to work and is not something you
can get with offthe shelf retrievers or
even as far as I know the best
retrievers you can get right now and so
I believe there will be many of these
things many extra pieces many extra
models that will combine into one system
system that provides the best possible
user experience we haven't figured out
what all these things are yet but there
are clearly these other components that
are needed to automate to get the most
value we can out of AI for code cool
super interesting I I think you veered
into models on it so I think that's an
interesting question so you're not
training the model you're doing rag
again simplistically put you can do rag
on top of any model and pull it out
maybe tell us a little bit about what is
your approach to models and and why you
building your own models and I think you
have a bit of a history over here
learning kind of so it just be
interesting to hear how your perspective
has evolved uh over time yeah so first
at a high level it it's a mix we are
also actually training models because it
it depends on the feature and what model
is driving it but for most of the
features we do end up having to both
train models and do the retrieval for it
all to work together so there's actually
a substantial amount of training that
happens
the thing we don't do though is we don't
train models from scratch we don't do
pre-training and that was a bet we made
very early on when we started open-
Source models were nowhere near what
they are now the best even the best open
source code models were quite bad
compared to what we have now but we made
the bet that they will catch up and they
will become excellent and the reason we
made that bet is because I guess one
reason is at Google I saw what goes into
pre-training models and at that point
there was almost a Playbook you had to
go get data you have to clean it D
duplicate it you need a bunch of gpus
and need to train on them and you need
to watch out for GPU failures and
there's a whole list of things you have
to do and it's very challenging but
there is a Playbook and if you follow
the Playbook you will get a good model
out of it and then the game becomes okay
how can I squeeze more out of the model
how can I improve a little bit more on
data quality and all these things matter
a lot but I'd say based on that the BET
was open source can do that it's
happened much faster than I expected and
to a greater degree than I expected that
seems to be a recurring pattern in the
world of AI is always faster than we
think absolutely so open source is like
that as well we've fairly quickly got
access to extremely good base models for
code so these are not models that you
can take and put in your product as is
and they will drive your completions so
just to give an example or completions
or any other feature to give an example
besides rag there are other things that
are important if I'm getting a
completion around the cursor the model
needs to take in into account what's
before the cursor what's after the
cursor it needs to give me a completion
that stops at the right point this is
not something that any off-the-shelf
model that I've seen can do well
currently and so there are things like
that that we need to train the models to
do well which go beyond rag rag is of
course like a big piece of it but the
thing is the better the base model you
start with the better the pre-train
model you start with you can put that
extra training on top and you can get uh
a much better model at the end and so
our approach is that we keep up with the
best open source models they still are
coming out regularly and it's very nice
to see that after the general purpose
models the next thing you get are the
code specific models this still seems to
be happening which is great for us and
so we will do a lot of training on top
of Open Source models but we don't do
our own uh pre-training and then we will
do rag yeah yeah I'm curious this is a
bit of a philosophical question I think
to both of you got the own I guess the
in in the world of of true open source
because we say open source models I
think like probably open weights models
have often times been been described now
like this but in open source there's a
way to contribute back so as an
ecosystem you can talk about some piece
of software that is open source that
becomes better and better because once
it gets kubernetes or Linux or something
like that because a bunch of interested
parties that are all sharing the use of
this they come in and they contribute
back in these open weights models as far
as I understand it's very hard to
contribute back you can report bugs you
can do things but it's not actually open
source you don't typically orever
actually see the data set just available
to you and say hey I'm going to correct
this data or add to this data how do you
maybe two in one types question is like
one is what would make these open source
models win in the long run at the moment
feels a little bit like they're the
Goodwill of business strategy of certain
organizations that are publishing them
and hosting it and then related to that
if you do want to engage and tweak bug
fix or contribute back to the open waste
models is that possible yeah this good
question so I'd say what will make them
win so to me this is more of course it's
it's competitive in some sense but the
way I think about it is more as an
ecosystem of models
we have different models driving our
different features there's a whole
Spectrum in terms of the size of the
model the latency you get and how do you
match that to the appropriate feature
and how specific is the feature how
General is it and sometimes we use
closed Source closed models sometimes we
use open weights models I think it's a
good distinction open source versus open
weights because indeed we don't for
almost all these models we don't have
access to the full training recipe so I
would say in terms of who wins
yes the reality is that overall staying
at the frontier or being close to the
frontier requires more and more compute
resources and so more Capital over time
we keep seeing optimizations which is
natural because once something works and
the quality is good usually you go back
and you find like a whole list of things
you can improve to do better and that
includes training and so we are
regularly seeing small models coming out
that are performing as well as models
that were 10x larger before and so that
still often takes us back to the regime
where oh this task that used to be Out
Of Reach for many groups because they
didn't have a lot of compute now you can
get that with a smaller model we saw
that again and again it happened with
Lama I would say it happened with quen
more recently it's still happening there
seems to be still a lot of room for
optimization but overall yes I think
it's true that to stay close to the
frontier it's going to require more and
more capital resources yeah on the
smaller side of the models I don't
really see a reason why folks can't stay
on the frontier because if your latency
requirements are fairly strict then for
a while I I believe we will stay on
smaller models and so then it also is
less effort to train them also the
smaller models don't benefit as you can
throw 100x more data at them but it's
not like they can learn all that data
anyway so overall the computer sources
are but to challenge that a little bit
guys like all of those are the reasons
why if I'm building a model and then I'm
opening it or sharing the weights of it
it is less expensive for me to to do it
but it's still expensive for me to do it
like I I'm still opening it and so I'm
curious about the sort of the second
part of the question which is how do you
contribute how do you benefit from a
community using an open weights model
and maybe it's a question even like
specifically a augment like how do you
contribute back to those models when you
decide to do it I'm not asking how often
you're doing it that's a sort of a
business choice but when you do it what
are even your options yeah the options
I'd say we I think we'd love to
contribute back because we've benefited
a lot from the open weights models but
it it's fairly limited our our options
are very limited I think it's more of a
research to me it's more of a research
problem once you're handed the weights
you can push them forward by continuing
to fine-tune and making the model better
on more specific tasks that you care
about so you can do that but going in
fixing things let's say I found that the
model makes a mistake right and it's a
recurring pattern and whenever I show it
certain kinds of inputs it makes that
mistake if this was an open source
program I could go I could fix it I
could submit a poll request right it's
easy but with models we don't have that
level of control over the models at the
end there's still a black box and
there's research certainly on
interpretability and I think some of
that research is aimed at can we go in
there and figure out which neurons
control which inputs and which outputs
and when there is a problem can we go
change those particular neurons and fix
them that research is still at an
earlier stage than just our ability to
train a blackbox model the best path I
see for us to be able to contribute back
is if that research pans out and we get
a set of tools where we can start
submitting patches to models right would
be great if we had the weights we could
fix a problem and then we go and submit
a patch now it's not a source patch it's
some patch to the weights but just apply
this patch and your model will get
slightly better on these problems that
would be analogous to what we see with
open source we don't have that ability
right now because we're limited on
Research yeah indeed D do you have any
views on this yeah I think I'm very
happy that we don't call non-open Source
models even when some companies try and
sneak that into their releases but
there's tons of value in the open weight
models so I don't want to dissuade that
from happening and you do see things
where people just more into the are able
into the overall ecosystem of
contributing various Tools around these
things because they feel like in general
there's more openness and availability
there so there there's Nuance right
there's a bunch of Open Source projects
where I know that if I put a PR in it's
not going to be accepted never be it's
open source but it doesn't actually
matter in that case right so I think
there is a bunch of open Nuance to to
all of these things but it's been nice
to see the the direction that we're
going in just the raw competition in
this space is the thing that matters I
think more than anything else so we're
not locked in yeah yeah we definitely
benefit as a community from open weights
models including hment like a good
example of that and so I'm happy they're
doing it there's open research
collaboration on it but that ironically
also happens with the closed models on
it I don't know if it's more or less
common amidst open weights models than
than the closed ones but it's just
interesting like I I find myself
pondering the especially when we do call
it open source which is unnatural I'm
not fuss about the fact that people you
know whatever use the sort of the
slightly inaccurate term for it uh but I
more think if you call it open source
the reason we keep saying open source
will win is because the community will
come together and this is actually a
place in which the community cannot
fully come together they can encourage
they can support an organization uh but
eventually there's some amount of if
you're using Cod LMA or three whatever
you're at the mirror SE a bit of the
continued strategy of meta to publish
the next version after they've spend
whatever many million dollars on yeah
maybe to add one comment to this let's
say there are open source mod there are
models that are completely open source
you have access to the training scripts
you can see their training logs and W DB
you see all their training data and how
they collected it it's all there right
they're fully open source but still if I
find a problem with that model and I
want to fix it the only thing I can do
do is go back to the training data and
change it assuming I understand this is
the same problem you mentioned before
with fine tuning if you see a problem
you have to go back to the data and
change it to fine tune and it's all very
indirect and then I have to spend all
the time and effort to train them all
again and check if I fix the problem
yeah so even if I have access to
everything I still am very limited in
what I can contribute it's a huge
project to submit like a bug fix to the
model yeah so that to me is really what
it boils down to it's wonderful when
people and we benefit from that as well
it's wonderful when people open source
everything very useful but we're really
gated on our ability to to go and patch
and fix these models yeah yeah it's a
good point open weights versus source is
one Delta but there's also just the
sheer scale and
interpretability that get in the way as
well so guys this conversation been
great on it flying through time over
here and conversations it clearly the
augment is a very powerful product today
and it goes in and it helps a human
developer uh write code in the IDE and
today I believe it does autoc completion
it also does chat based generation on it
and a lot of these patterns are emerging
amidst coding assistants and amidst
users of coding assistants who learn
what to expect let's cast our eyes a
little bit to the Future and I guess for
starters do you think people will still
need an ID completion Solution on it in
call it five years time like when you
think about indeed the journey towards
more autonomous coding yeah that's an
interesting question five years in this
space is like eternity so everything I a
century roughly a century yeah feels
like that and so this is completely
speculative let's say it like this I
think on it depends on the task you're
trying to solve right if you're trying
to solve something that's on the simpler
side let's say in five years some
percent of issues coming into a a
workspace are they going to be
automatically fixed unpatched by models
yes I I think that's essentially a
guarantee but now the question is of
these issues that are coming in what is
it going to be is it going to be like
20% 50% probably depends on the project
is there going to be uh still a good
amount of of issues that developers will
have to go in and dig in and fix
themselves I would say again I really
like the self-driving analogy because
it's not that it's a simpler task but at
least the action space is is a lot
simpler right you have your steering
wheel you have your pedals we still have
not solved full self-driving but we're
getting a lot of value along the way
from more and more more automation
coding is a richer task in terms of at
least the action space the reasoning is
different there's definitely different
kinds of reasoning that go into it what
I expect my guess is that yes I think
completions will still be relevant from
what I'm seeing so far the better the
tools become it's not that I end up just
doing the same work that I did before
faster using these tools and so using
less completions or less next edit or
whatever it is I'm using what ends up
happening is that I actually end up
accomplishing a lot more and I end up
using yeah I use some amount of time
let's say in chat I use some of amount
of time in other features I still use
completions a lot because it's still
happens a lot that I need to go in and
make changes manually and when I do that
sometimes it's a lot of code and when I
do that I really want to have
completions there with me and I want
them to be context aware and I think
that's especially true in the larger
more complex code bases because those
are the ones that are going to get
automated the slowest because those are
the hardest to deal with so five years
is a long time but I still expect these
tools to be around for a while even as
we add more and more Automation and let
people write more and more code using
natural language which is like very
clearly the trend I expect these tools
to all live together I guess though if I
let me try to attempt at trying slightly
longer timelines so if you're a software
developer today Junior to mid-level
software developer what skills do you
need to build out to be successful in
your career given Evolution given the
anticipated growth in ability of
solutions such as augment yes so I think
I would point to two things that seem to
me to be essential will continue to be
essential for the foreseeable future
first I think for the foreseeable future
these models will keep making a lot of
mistakes the software systems that we
have are already incredibly complex and
the more AI automation we have they will
just get more and more complex and they
mess up the AI systems mess up a lot and
when that happens there's no replacement
to having a deep understanding of how
the system works I don't think that's I
I don't think that's going to go away
and so in my experience I can use
augment to crank out hundreds thousands
of lines of code sometimes it all works
great it all works fine for a while and
then something goes wrong and when
something goes wrong I still need to
have the understanding of how the system
works what is it built on full stack
understanding often of what things are
for me to be able to go and and fix
things when augment can't fix it for me
so I don't think that depth of knowledge
of course has always been important in
programming I don't think that's going
to go away on the totally other end of
the spectrum it has become very
important I I'd say to understand these
models and understand how to prompt them
to get the most value out of them we are
still at a point where the thing cannot
read your mind and so there's certainly
a lot of tricks into it's it's a whole
skill set how do you get the most value
out of these models at this point and of
course us and everyone else are are
constantly trying to make that less of a
challenge and make it as seamless as
possible but still the models the more
you learn about the models and how they
work and how to get the more value out
of them that skill set will I believe
for now just become more valuable over
time so these are like two very extreme
ends of the spectrum that I think a
developer entering the field would
benefit from yeah we might be nitpicking
a little bit on timelines but I think
both of those things while I 100% agree
with them today I guess the question is
what's their longevity like the models
and the tools around them should really
get better at the prompting like they
they're never going to read your mind
they better understand the context they
better understand the surrounding and so
it should be easier to prompt and so
it's almost like if you invest right now
in prompt engineering a lot of these
things you're going to need to learn
this has already been proven right if
you were really proficient at I know in
image models it's easy right like if you
got into your diffusion models and into
your stability words and then you got
into me journey and just used English
today but and I think on the other side
like the system wouldn't augment to be
dramatically smarter in five years time
and its understanding of the ecosystem
like how many people on the team would
really have a better understanding don't
you need to break down systems and know
how to elaborate and that's always going
to be true right is just you get to
understand not so much remember the
whole system but rather know how to
engage with some presented knowledge of
the system exactly I guess the extreme
question that I have that I like maybe
literally a bunch of us parents would be
facing is would you recommend to your
kid right now to go do a CS degree
that's a hard question I think my answer
to that question changes at this point
almost on a monthly basis at this point
I am not sure I am not sure it's really
hard to predict because on the one hand
yes I I agree with everything you said
it it it it will of course get easier
that is what I'm working on every day
right it's just we're in this industry
and it's a good thing like more people
will create more things more easily it's
a good thing it just has impacts on the
profession that's right yes exactly it's
it's all good for society uh also just
on the comment on prompt engineering
just to clarify yes I I don't think
people should go and study to become
prompt Engineers I guess maybe to
summarize that point Point what I'm
trying to say is just I think what
happens a lot is people will try the
models and get something out of them
sometimes it's good sometimes it's not
good and they will assume that yeah this
is the value we can get from the model
there is more out there that that's
really my message P it try try to push
it in all kinds of directions to learn
what the limits are I think often people
would try it out and they say okay this
is it this is where the level of of
quality is and yes that will become
easier over time but you can get a lot
out of these models if you try to push
them on the question of the Cs degree so
first of all I I I do believe in
humanity and I think getting a CS degree
for the purpose of learning deep things
about the world is still a valuable
thing to do I think in terms of a career
choice I have to say I'm on the
optimistic side here because I think
implicit in these discussions is this
thought that there is there's this
assumption maybe implicit assumption
that there is a finite amount of things
we were going to want to build
and with AI we're going to automate it
and there's going to be nothing left to
build if I look back at the history of
programming every time a new programming
language came out the whole point of it
was to automate away the chores and the
toil of the previous language make it
easier to write software right but at
the same time the amount of software we
write and the complexity has just
skyrocketed it's it's not that the new
languages have made us like allow us to
just do our job in five minutes and go
to the beach no we just build more and
bigger things so this is complete
speculation but my belief is that what
we will see is just far more advanced
complex and useful systems that will
come out of AI and that there will still
be room for humans to to steer these
systems and yes that I do believe you
will still need a deep understanding of
what happens now I think one data point
that will make me rethink that is if we
manage to actually solve self-driving
end to end and completely get rid of
that task fully then maybe yes maybe I
can see how other real world tasks
succumb to that as well and maybe it
will happen but overall example would
you want someone would you invest in
whatever becoming a taxi driver right
now or a professional driver I think the
spectrum of developers is so different
than driver though there's certain
developers who I would trust to
contribute to the chromium or the Linux
kernel it's like a small subset compared
to the one I would trust to build a web
app they're not the same things right
there's very different levels of things
that are going on so what does my kid
want to do what layer of abstraction do
they want to live in for this right what
kind of Cs degree are they actually
getting right there's many different
types now right so I think there's I
definitely would love my kids to make
that choice if depending on what they
wanted to do and I want to democratize
this for them and I want them to be
focused on solving real problems s and
so being able to live at higher level
abstractions to build bigger things like
that sounds great to me it doesn't seem
like the worst degree to get yeah yeah
I'm inan uh just not that I'm in the
optimistic camp in terms of there will
be things to build and I think being a
software creator is something that we
will need in a decade in two decades in
five decades or whatever solution
Creator on it with software I have a lot
less conviction around the computer
science degree being able to keep up
with the pace of change there I'm like a
very very much a short seller I am not
optimistic about that being the correct
training even today I'd say it's dubious
yeah if you're going to go and do a PhD
in machine learning then somewhere in
computer science and and math is is
probably a good place to be uh if you're
going to go build even contribute to the
Linux kernel or the equivalent future
crazy world of AI power development even
then I'm not certain that that a
computer science degree would give you
the tools that you need to be doing that
type of work in a decade or two so I
guess we won't know but it's a very real
question right because our kids will be
grappling with that it's a real question
I think it's trying to predict both like
the the technology advances and the the
the job in some sense you're trying to
predict the job market situation which
depends on the technology depends on how
much stuff we'll need to build the
competition uh maybe if I stay on the
optimistic side I would expect CS
degrees to evolve let's say because if
there's room for people to create
software and it does require a deep
understanding of systems then I would
hope that the degrees do evolve to to
match that but yes we're going to find
out we'll find out gu this has been
excellent the conversation on it I feel
like we can continue it on but I think
we're starting to really stretch the
attention span of the listeners for a
single episode maybe guy just one bit if
people want to check out augment or try
out what's like a one call to action
you'd give them yeah go to augment
code.com click get augment and start
coding reach out to us with any feedback
good or bad if you want to talk to us if
you have feature requests if you see
things that you see you would love to
have in the product if you just want to
chat about AI for code reach out we'll
be happy to chat we love talking to our
users sounds good awesome this was great
thanks thanks again for coming on to
both of you and thanks everybody for
tuning in and I hope you join us for the
next one Cheers
Cheers thanks for tuning in join us next
time on the AI native Dev brought to you
by Tesla
[Music]